[English subtitles are available]
[الترجمة الإنجليزية متوفرة]
[See You Again]
[نراكم مرة أخرى]
[Episode 26]
[الحلقة 26]
It's so serious.
إنه أمر خطير للغاية.
Why didn't you go to the hospital to bandage it?
لماذا لم تذهب إلى المستشفى لتضميده؟
I'm fine.
أنا بخير.
Just a minor injury.
مجرد إصابة طفيفة.
You call this a minor injury?
هل تسمي هذا إصابة طفيفة؟
I've seen wolves in the wild.
لقد رأيت الذئاب في البرية.
My skin is thick.
بشرتي سميكة.
Besides,
بجانب،
I might even enjoy the care of you.
قد أستمتع حتى برعايتك.
Jin Chuan, can you promise me
جين تشوان ، هل يمكنك أن تعدني
no matter what you do in the future,
بغض النظر عما ستفعله في المستقبل ،
the bottom line is to protect yourself？
بيت القصيد هو حماية نفسك？
Don't let those who care about you worry about you anymore.
لا تدع من يهتم لأمرك يقلق عليك بعد الآن.
I saw
لقد رأيت
the message you left me.
الرسالة التي تركتها لي.
Where have you been?
أين كنت؟
I had some problems at work
لدي بعض المشاكل في العمل
and I went to solve them.
وذهبت لحلها.
Could it be
هل من الممكن ذلك
because of me and my sister?
بسببي و اختي؟
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
I didn't mean to hide
لم أقصد الاختباء
the fact that Jin Ayin is my sister.
حقيقة أن جين عين هي أختي.
I was afraid
كنت خائفا
because of me,
بسببي،
you two would be influenced.
أنتما الاثنان ستتأثران.
So in your heart,
لذلك في قلبك ،
I can't tell right from wrong?
لا أستطيع التمييز بين الصواب والخطأ؟
No, that's not what I meant.
لا ، ليس هذا ما قصدته.
Don't be nervous.
لا تكن عصبيا.
It's really not because of that.
إنه في الحقيقة ليس بسبب ذلك.
But
ولكن
I want to talk to you
أريد أن أتحدث إليك
about us.
معلومات عنا.
You really like drinking.
أنت حقا تحب الشرب.
It can help me relax.
يمكن أن يساعدني على الاسترخاء.
Drinking some is good for the mood.
شرب القليل مفيد للمزاج.
Drinking too much is bad for your health.
الإفراط في الشرب يضر بصحتك.
You might be able to live to 100 years old if you don't drink.
قد تتمكن من العيش حتى 100 عام إذا لم تشرب.
What's the point of
ما المغزى من
living cautiously and being 100 years old?
يعيش بحذر ويبلغ عمره 100 عام؟
That's what I like about you.
هذا ما يعجبني بشأنك.
Straightforward?
مباشر؟
That's because
هذا بسبب
since the first time I got the short end of the stick,
منذ المرة الأولى التي حصلت فيها على الطرف القصير من العصا ،
I knew that
علمت ذلك
as long as
طالما
you are capable,
انت قادر
you don't have to pretend.
ليس عليك التظاهر.
Then why do you like me?
إذن لماذا تحبني؟
Just like the photo you took.
تمامًا مثل الصورة التي التقطتها.
The fish in water and the lion in the painting
السمكة في الماء والأسد في اللوحة
are from two completely different worlds.
من عالمين مختلفين تمامًا.
But they met magically.
لكنهم التقوا بطريقة سحرية.
Maybe it can be
ربما يمكن أن يكون
a wonderful journey.
رحلة رائعة.
But why can't they
لكن لماذا لا يستطيعون ذلك
have a happy ending?
نهاية سعيدة؟
This is why
هذا هو السبب
I get angry because you stayed for me.
أنا غاضب لأنك بقيت من أجلي.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
If it were another girl,
لو كانت فتاة أخرى
it would be
سيكون من
a happy thing.
شيء سعيد.
But you really don't have to do this for me.
لكن ليس عليك فعل ذلك من أجلي.
I don't need
لست بحاجة
a relationship in which two people sacrifice for each other.
علاقة يضحي فيها شخصان من أجل بعضهما البعض.
Don't you want me to stay by your side?
ألا تريدني أن أبقى بجانبك؟
But what I don't want more
لكن ما لا أريده أكثر
is you changing yourself.
هل تغير نفسك.
Do you want to hear
هل تريد أن تسمع
my old-fashioned first love story?
قصة حبي الأولى القديمة؟
I don't tell everyone.
لا أخبر الجميع.
We were college classmates.
كنا زملاء جامعيين.
After graduation,
بعد التخرج،
I came to Beijing with him.
جئت إلى بكين معه.
When I really needed to work hard for myself,
عندما احتجت حقًا إلى العمل الجاد من أجل نفسي ،
I chose to
اخترت
give him a warm home.
أعطه منزلًا دافئًا.
When he went out to work,
عندما خرج للعمل ،
I stayed at home,
بقيت في المنزل،
cleaning, cooking for him,
التنظيف والطبخ له ،
cleaning the floor, doing the laundry,
تنظيف الأرضية والغسيل
and preparing three meals a day.
وتحضير ثلاث وجبات في اليوم.
My whole living space seemed to be home
يبدو أن مساحة المعيشة الخاصة بي بالكامل هي المنزل
and the grocery.
والبقالة.
Until one day,
حتى يوم واحد،
when I went grocery shopping,
عندما ذهبت لشراء البقالة ،
I suddenly felt
شعرت فجأة
I didn't want to live like this forever.
لا أريد أن أعيش هكذا إلى الأبد.
Then I threw the vegetables on the floor.
ثم رميت الخضار على الأرض.
I told him at night
قلت له في الليل
that I was leaving.
أني كنت أغادر.
What's funny was
ما هو مضحك كان
I didn't realize until then that
لم أدرك ذلك حتى ذلك الحين
he was tired of it, too.
لقد سئم منها أيضًا.
It's just a pity
إنه أمر مؤسف
to throw it away.
لرميها بعيدا.
So do you understand now?
هل تفهم الآن؟
I don't let you stay for me
أنا لا أسمح لك بالبقاء من أجلي
not only because you need to fulfill your dream,
ليس فقط لأنك تحتاج إلى تحقيق حلمك ،
but because...
ولكن...
Because I can't bear other people's lives.
لأنني لا أستطيع تحمل حياة الآخرين.
If one day,
إذا في يوم من الأيام ،
I have a better chance and need to leave,
لدي فرصة أفضل وأحتاج إلى المغادرة ،
I won't stay for you, either.
لن أبقى من أجلك أيضًا.
Or...
أو...
I'm a selfish woman from the beginning.
أنا امرأة أنانية من البداية.
Chuan,
إذا،
You can resent me,
يمكنك الاستياء مني ،
or even hate me.
أو حتى تكرهني.
But if possible,
لكن إذا أمكن ،
I really hope we can
آمل حقًا أن نتمكن من ذلك
learn something
تعلم شيئا
from the circle of
من دائرة
owning temporarily but losing forever.
التملك مؤقتًا ولكن الخسارة إلى الأبد.
♫The broken, messy, dried from tears♫
♫ المكسور ، الفوضوي ، المجفف من الدموع ♫
♫The painful, anxious, and struggling dream♫
الحلم المؤلم والقلق والمكافح ♫
♫My faith♫
♫ إيماني ♫
♫Is in your hand♫
في يدك ♫
♫I'm not afraid of the words of loving you♫
♫ لا أخاف من كلام حبك ♫
♫I see the light in the distance♫
♫ أرى الضوء في المسافة ♫
♫But it is a bit dim♫
♫ لكنها قاتمة بعض الشيء
♫I will light you up with it♫
♫ سأضيءك بها
♫As I'm still alive♫
♫ بما أنني ما زلت على قيد الحياة
♫Darkness♫
ظلام ♫
♫Is along the way that I try to find you♫
♫ على طول الطريق الذي أحاول أن أجده ♫
♫Release♫
♫ تحرير ♫
♫Craziness♫
الجنون ♫
♫Is surrounding the dark♫
يحيط بالظلمة ♫
♫Who is yelling?♫
من الذي يصرخ؟
♫Darkness♫
ظلام ♫
♫I'm never afraid of your pain♫
♫ أنا لا أخاف أبدًا من ألمك
♫It vanishes in the end♫
تختفي في النهاية ♫
♫Darkness♫
ظلام ♫
♫Makes me reborn♫
♫ يجعلني ولدت من جديد ♫
♫In suffocation♫
في الاختناق ♫
♫I see the light in the distance♫
♫ أرى الضوء في المسافة ♫
♫Become brighter gradually♫
♫ تصبح أكثر إشراقًا تدريجيًا ♫
♫I will light you up with it♫
♫ سأضيءك بها
[Life is worth it.]
[الحياة تستحق كل هذا العناء.]
[Every step counts.]
[كل خطوة مهمة.]
♫As I'm still alive♫
♫ بما أنني ما زلت على قيد الحياة
♫Darkness♫
ظلام ♫
♫Is along the way that I try to find you♫
♫ على طول الطريق الذي أحاول أن أجده ♫
♫Release♫
♫ تحرير ♫
♫Craziness♫
الجنون ♫
♫Is surrounding the dark♫
يحيط بالظلمة ♫
♫Who is yelling?♫
من الذي يصرخ؟
♫Darkness♫
ظلام ♫
♫I'm never afraid of your pain♫
♫ أنا لا أخاف أبدًا من ألمك
♫It vanishes in the end♫
تختفي في النهاية ♫
♫Darkness♫
ظلام ♫
♫Makes me reborn♫
♫ يجعلني ولدت من جديد ♫
♫In suffocation♫
في الاختناق ♫
Home is the most comfortable.
المنزل هو الأكثر راحة.
Xiang Qinyu.
شيانغ تشينيو.
Where is he?
أين هو؟
[I'll be back soon.]
[سأعود قريبا.]
Wait.
انتظر.
Coming.
آت.
Jin Ayin.
جين عين.
Why do you always
لماذا انت دائما
disappear from me frequently?
تختفي عني كثيرا؟
How could you not tell me
كيف لا تستطيع أن تخبرني
such a big thing happened?
حدث مثل هذا الشيء الكبير؟
Let go.
اتركه.
You disappeared on the day of the movie
لقد اختفيت في يوم الفيلم
and went to find some master for no reason.
وذهبت لتجد معلما بدون سبب.
I was waiting for you
كنت أنتظرك
to tell me what you have been doing lately?
لتخبرني ماذا كنت تفعل مؤخرا؟
But you,
لكنك،
you got into the hospital.
دخلت المستشفى.
Thanks to Li Yongda's slip of the tongue on the set,
بفضل زلة لسان Li Yongda على المجموعة ،
I found it out.
لقد اكتشفت ذلك.
I was creating chances
كنت أصنع الفرص
for you and Longda.
لك ولونجدا.
Don't talk nonsense.
لا تتحدث عن هراء.
What chance?
ما فرصة؟
-I'll be angry if you keep talking. -I'm wrong.
-سأغضب إذا واصلت الحديث.  -انا مخطئ.
-I'm sorry. -Stop right there.
-أنا آسف.  -توقف هناك.
I'll stop.
سوف أتوقف.
-I'll stop. -I'm back.
-سوف أتوقف.  -لقد عدت.
My dinosaur.
ديناصور بلدي.
Why is it here?
لماذا هو هنا؟
Did you win it back?
هل استعادتها؟
It's nothing.
إنه لاشيء.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
هيا.  هيا.  هيا.
Look.
نظرة.
You really look like this dinosaur.
أنت حقا تبدو مثل هذا الديناصور.
It looks like you.
انه يشبهك.
Look at your short hands.
انظر إلى يديك القصيرة.
-It's so long. -Is it the same?
-انه طويل جدا.  -هل هو نفسه؟
Your teeth are the same as its.
أسنانك هي نفسها.
Look at your smile.
انظر إلى ابتسامتك.
Look at your mouth.
انظر إلى فمك.
-You look more alike when you smile. -Look at your smile.
- تبدو أكثر تشابهاً عندما تبتسم.  -انظر إلى ابتسامتك.
-Look at the cheeks. -You’re just like it.
-نظري إلى الخدين.  -أنت فقط مثل ذلك.
Look at the cheeks.
انظر إلى الخدين.
If I'm guilty,
إذا كنت مذنبًا ،
the law will punish me,
القانون سوف يعاقبني ،
instead of forcing me to watch
بدلا من إجباري على المشاهدة
your old-fashioned display of love.
عرضك القديم للحب.
Let's go to the hospital to see Taotao.
دعنا نذهب إلى المستشفى لنرى Taotao.
Aren't you two
ألستم الاثنان
the ones on the news yesterday?
الذين ظهروا في الأخبار أمس؟
So Ma is really...
إذن ما هو حقًا ...
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
I... I don't know Ma is that kind of person.
أنا ... لا أعرف ما هو هذا النوع من الأشخاص.
It's okay.
حسنا.
I won't disturb you.
لن أزعجك.
Well,
نحن سوف،
excuse me.
عفوا.
Can I have some of your time?
هل يمكنني الحصول على بعض من وقتك؟
We want to know something.
نريد أن نعرف شيئا.
Ma brought it here a few days ago.
ما أحضره هنا قبل بضعة أيام.
Try it.
جربها.
Every time he came,
في كل مرة يأتي ،
he would bring different stuff for us nurses.
كان سيحضر أشياء مختلفة لنا كممرضات.
I said we could not accept it,
قلت لا يمكننا قبوله ،
but I couldn't stop him.
لكنني لم أستطع منعه.
We all know
نعلم جميعا
he did this
لقد فعل هذا
for Taotao.
لـ Taotao.
He came to see Taotao almost every day.
كان يأتي ليرى Taotao كل يوم تقريبًا.
He
هو
spent all his money
أنفق كل ماله
on the medical fees.
على الرسوم الطبية.
He believes that one day
يعتقد ذلك في يوم من الأيام
she will wake up again.
سوف تستيقظ مرة أخرى.
I've seen many cases
لقد رأيت العديد من الحالات
that people cannot hold on because the patient is in hospital for too long.
لا يستطيع الناس تحملها لأن المريض في المستشفى لفترة طويلة.
But I've never seen
لكني لم أر قط
anyone like him,
أي شخص مثله ،
guarding someone no matter what.
حراسة شخص ما مهما كان الأمر.
Although Taotao has no family,
على الرغم من أن Taotao ليس له عائلة ،
Ma treats her
ما يعاملها
really well.
جيد حقا.
I have other patients to take care of.
لدي مرضى آخرين لأعتني بهم.
I'm leaving.
سأغادر.
I'll pay for Taotao's fee.
سأدفع رسوم Taotao.
No matter what Ze is like,
بغض النظر عن شكل زي ،
I'll take care of her.
سأعتني بها.
What happened
ماذا حدث
to you indeed?
لك حقا؟
I still don't know your name.
ما زلت لا أعرف اسمك.
You know it.
أنت تعرفها.
I told you before.
أخبرتك من قبل.
But you forgot.
لكنك نسيت.
Yu.
يو.
Do you remember me?
هل تتذكرني؟
My name is
اسمي هو
Yang Xiaoyun.
يانغ شياو يون.
Yang Xiaoyun?
يانغ شياو يون؟
You're Yang Xiaoyun, right?
أنت يانغ شياو يون ، أليس كذلك؟
I've paid the fees.
لقد دفعت الرسوم.
What are you looking at?
الى ماذا تنظرين؟
[Yang Xiaoyun Committed Suicide]
[انتحر يانغ شياويون]
If this person was an actress,
إذا كان هذا الشخص ممثلة ،
do you remember
هل تذكر
the name of the films she acted in?
ما اسم الأفلام التي مثلت فيها؟
Yang Xiaoyun.
يانغ شياو يون.
You are an actress.
انت ممثلة.
Why are you so shy?
لماذا انت خجول جدا؟
If the audience likes it,
إذا أعجب الجمهور ،
you have to take off your clothes and show them.
عليك خلع ملابسك وإظهارها.
[Romantic and Sexy Story]
[قصة رومانسية ومثيرة]
[Director: Yuan Zifeng]
[المخرج: يوان زيفنغ]
Romantic and Sexy Story
قصة رومانسية ومثيرة
Got it.
فهمتك.
The movie Romantic and Sexy Story
قصة فيلم رومانسي ومثير
was forced to stop
اضطر للتوقف
because the female lead passed away suddenly during the process of filming.
لأن البطلة ماتت فجأة أثناء عملية التصوير.
Different opinions aroused.
أثيرت آراء مختلفة.
There were many guesses.
كان هناك الكثير من التخمينات.
Yang Xiaoyun.
يانغ شياو يون.
Where do you think this is?
أين تعتقد هذا؟
You think
انت تفكر
you can shoot or not as you wish?
يمكنك اطلاق النار ام لا كما يحلو لك؟
Where do you think this is?
أين تعتقد هذا؟
You don't want to shoot?
لا تريد أن تطلق النار؟
Come on.
هيا.
Take it off.
انزعها.
The main rumor is that
الشائعة الرئيسية هي أن
the director forced the actress
أجبر المخرج الممثلة
to do some erotic acting,
للقيام ببعض التمثيل المثيرة ،
and the female lead committed suicide by jumping out of the building
وانتحرت البطلة بالقفز من المبنى
because she could not endure the shame and bully.
لأنها لم تستطع تحمل العار والبلطجة.
Yu.
يو.
Open the door.
افتح الباب.
Only you can save me.
فقط يمكنك أن تنقذني.
Help me.
ساعدني.
Yu.
يو.
Here.
هنا.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Are you okay?
هل انت بخير؟
I've just realized
لقد أدركت للتو
how wrong I was.
كم كنت مخطئا.
Actually, Chi Yu and I are the same.
في الواقع ، أنا وتشي يو متماثلان.
We didn't realize
لم ندرك
at that time,
فى ذلك التوقيت،
it was their last SOS to us.
كانت آخر استغاثة لهم لنا.
My ignoring to Yang Xiaoyun
تجاهلي لـ Yang Xiaoyun
is just like what Chi Yu said
هو تماما مثل ما قاله تشي يو
to Taotao at that time,
إلى Taotao في ذلك الوقت ،
pushing her to the tragedy in the end.
دفعها إلى المأساة في النهاية.
If there's a chance,
إذا كانت هناك فرصة ،
I want to go back and tell her
أريد أن أعود وأخبرها
not to
لا
pay for others' mistakes.
دفع ثمن أخطاء الآخرين.
Life is the most precious.
الحياة هي أثمن.
As long as you live,
طالما كنت تعيش،
there will be hope.
سيكون هناك أمل.
Unfortunately,
للأسف،
it's too late.
فات الأوان.
It was me
لقد كان أنا
who broke her only lifeline.
الذي كسر شريان حياتها الوحيد.
Is this Taotao's cat?
هل هذا قط Taotao؟
Yes.
نعم.
Look how cute it is.
انظر كم هو لطيف.
A cat of over 10 years old.
قطة عمرها أكثر من 10 سنوات.
I've never seen
لم أرى أبدا
such an old cat in my life.
مثل هذه القطة القديمة في حياتي.
It's a pity that grandma doesn't like cats.
إنه لأمر مؤسف أن الجدة لا تحب القطط.
Although
رغم
I don't like animals,
انا لا احب الحيوانات
it won't
لن تفعل ذلك
shed if it has some clothes on, right?
تسليط إذا كان يرتدي بعض الملابس ، أليس كذلك؟
You are dreaming.
أنت تحلم.
Answer it.
الإجابة عليه.
Hello.
مرحبًا.
Yu.
يو.
Happy birthday.
عيد مولد سعيد.
Today is your birthday.
اليوم هو عيد ميلادك.
I...
أنا...
I forgot.
انا نسيت.
Your mom said
قالت والدتك
you always spend your birthday
كنت دائما تقضي عيد ميلادك
outside with your friends.
بالخارج مع أصدقائك.
This year,
هذه السنة،
can we
هل نستطيع
spend your birthday
اقضي عيد ميلادك
together as a family?
معا كأسرة؟
Okay.
تمام.
OK.
نعم.
Well,
نحن سوف،
let's have dinner together tonight.
لنتناول العشاء معا الليلة.
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
See you tonight.
اراك الليلة.
Do you think
هل تعتقد
they find out?
اكتشفوا؟
What?
ماذا؟
I'm not their son.
أنا لست ابنهما.
No way.
مستحيل.
I think their tone is weird.
أعتقد أن لهجتهم غريبة.
I don't think so.
أنا لا أعتقد ذلك.
If they find out,
إذا اكتشفوا ،
why would they celebrate your birthday?
لماذا يحتفلون بعيد ميلادك؟
But what if...
ولكن ماذا لو...
There's no what if.
لا يوجد ماذا لو.
Aren't you an actor?
الا انت ممثل
You are experienced.
أنت من ذوي الخبرة.
The supermarket is right ahead.
السوبر ماركت في المقدمة مباشرة.
Let's go and see if there are any discounts.
دعنا نذهب ونرى ما إذا كان هناك أي خصومات.
Well...
نحن سوف...
How can four people
كيف يمكن لأربعة أشخاص
eat this much?
أكل هذا كثيرا؟
Didn't you say
لم تقل
70% off for shopping
70٪ خصم للتسوق
equals to paying nothing?
يساوي دفع لا شيء؟
This is too much.
هذا كثير للغاية.
It's the first time my girlfriend has got the chance to meet her parents-in-law.
إنها المرة الأولى التي تحصل فيها صديقتي على فرصة لمقابلة والدي زوجها.
It's good to prepare more.
من الجيد تحضير المزيد.
This is courtesy.
هذا مجاملة.
Why are you blushing?
لماذا تحمر خجلا؟
Let me see.
دعني أرى.
We are going to meet my parents soon.
سوف نلتقي بوالدي قريباً.
Have you figured out how to introduce yourself?
هل اكتشفت كيف تقدم نفسك؟
Haven't I
لا أنا
met them before?
التقى بهم من قبل؟
You're my girlfriend now.
أنت صديقتي الآن.
What if they ask
ماذا لو سألوا
how we met?
كيف التقينا؟
You can't say
لا يمكنك القول
I just appeared at your house, right?
لقد ظهرت للتو في منزلك ، أليس كذلك؟
Then how can I explain it?
ثم كيف لي أن أشرح ذلك؟
Nonsense.
كلام فارغ.
Teng Xi said
قال تنغ شي
people making friends online
الأشخاص الذين يكوّنون صداقات عبر الإنترنت
are
نكون
womanizers.
النساء.
We're not like people like that.
نحن لسنا مثل الناس من هذا القبيل.
Too vulgar.
مبتذلة جدا.
How about this?
وماذا عن هذا؟
The plot can be regarded new
يمكن اعتبار المؤامرة جديدة
in my era.
في عهدي.
Why don’t you change your career?
لماذا لا تغير مهنتك؟
Jin Ayin,
جين عين ،
if you are given another chance,
إذا أعطيت فرصة أخرى ،
how do you want to start?
كيف تريد ان تبدأ
After thinking about it,
بعد التفكير في الأمر ،
I still think
ما زلت أعتقد
the way you came that day,
بالطريقة التي جئت بها في ذلك اليوم ،
that I met you at my house,
أنني التقيت بك في منزلي ،
is the best beginning.
هي أفضل بداية.
A dark night,
ليلة مظلمة
when there were thunder and lightning,
عندما كان هناك رعد وبرق ،
you suddenly fell from the sky.
سقطت فجأة من السماء.
It's a bit thrilling,
إنه مثير بعض الشيء ،
but
لكن
no matter how romantic
مهما كانت رومانسية
our encounter becomes,
يصبح لقاءنا ،
I think
أظن
it's not half as good as the reality.
إنها ليست نصف جودة الواقع.
Here you go again.
ها أنت ذا مرة أخرى.
You pretended to kiss me
أنت تظاهرت بتقبيلي
and you'll laugh at me when I'm ready.
وستضحك علي عندما أكون جاهزًا.
I really want to this time...
أريد حقًا هذا الوقت ...
You're playing hard to get.
أنت تلعب بجد للحصول عليه.
I won't be fooled by you.
لن تنخدع بك.
Ayin.
عين.
I really wanted to kiss you. I swear.
أنا حقا أردت أن أقبلك.  أقسم.
Go away, scumbag.
اذهب بعيدا أيها النثر.
Go away.
يبتعد.
Coming.
آت.
Auntie, Uncle.
العمة ، العم.
You're here.
أنت هنا.
Come in.
ادخل.
Yu, happy birthday.
يو ، عيد ميلاد سعيد.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Uncle, Auntie,
العم ، العمة ،
Let's eat first.
دعونا نأكل أولاً.
Have a seat.
تفضل بالجلوس.
Sit. Okay.
يجلس.  تمام.
This house is quite nice.
هذا المنزل جميل جدا.
Happy birthday to you.
عيد ميلاد سعيد.
-Happy birthday. -Happy birthday.
-عيد مولد سعيد.  -عيد مولد سعيد.
Yu, make a wish.
يو ، تمنى أمنية.
Well...
نحن سوف...
Thank you, Mom.
شكرا لك أمي.
Thank you, Dad.
شكرا ابي.
Blow out the candles.
انفخ الشموع.
They're a good match.
إنها مباراة جيدة.
In the end,
فى النهاية،
they didn't ask me anything,
لم يسألوني عن أي شيء ،
I was worried that I might act badly.
كنت قلقة من أنني قد أتصرف بشكل سيء.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Let me do it.
دعني افعلها.
Go out and keep them company.
اخرج وحافظ على صحبتهم.
How cute.
كم لطيف.
Son,
ابن،
this cat is really like Jin said that no one takes care of it?
هذه القطة حقا مثلما قال جين أن لا أحد يهتم بها؟
Then I'll take it back to take care of it.
ثم سأعيدها لأعتني بها.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
I'm sure I will do it well.
أنا متأكد من أنني سأفعل ذلك بشكل جيد.
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
If I give it to you,
إذا أعطيته لك ،
Ayin's friend and I can rest assured.
يمكنني أن أطمئن أنا وصديق عين.
Kitty. Kitty.
كيتي.  كيتي.
I'm your owner now.
أنا مالكك الآن.
Look at me.
انظر إليَّ.
Honey. Honey.
عسل.  عسل.
Honey.
عسل.
I...
أنا...
I want to talk to our son.
اريد التحدث مع ابننا.
You help Jin.
أنت تساعد جين.
OK.
نعم.
I'm leaving. Don't quarrel with each other.
سأغادر.  لا تتشاجروا مع بعضهم البعض.
Son, have a seat.
بني ، أجلس.
Jin, are you busy?
جين ، هل أنت مشغول؟
Auntie.
العمة.
Here. Let me help you.
هنا.  دعني اساعدك.
No, no.
مهووس.
-I can do it myself. -What else do you need to do?
-أستطيع أن أفعل ذلك بنفسي.  -ماذا تحتاج أن تفعل أيضًا؟
-Have a seat. -Just sit and rest.
-تفضل بالجلوس.  - فقط اجلس واسترح.
Sit.
يجلس.
Yu,
يو ،
do you remember
هل تذكر
when you were little,
عندما كنت صغيرا،
there was a balcony like this in our old house?
كانت هناك شرفة كهذه في منزلنا القديم؟
One day,
يوم واحد،
you brought a box back,
لقد أحضرت صندوقًا ،
saying it was a tent
قائلا انها كانت خيمة
and wanted to camp there.
وأراد المخيم هناك.
That's the spot.
هذا هو المكان.
I got angry
لقد غضبت
and threw the box away.
وألقى الصندوق بعيدًا.
You brat,
أنت شقي،
you just lied there for a night.
لقد كذبت هناك ليلة واحدة.
Your mother
والدتك
forced me to buy you a real tent
أجبرني على شراء خيمة حقيقية لك
the next day.
في اليوم التالي.
Thanks to that.
بفضل ذلك.
In that whole summer,
في ذلك الصيف كله ،
I never saw you sleep on your bed anymore.
لم أرَك تنام على سريرك بعد الآن.
Son,
ابن،
since you were little,
منذ كنت صغيرا
I have been strict with you.
لقد كنت صارما معك.
I know that
وأنا أعلم ذلك
you are afraid of me.
انت خائف مني.
But how many sons
لكن كم عدد الأبناء
aren't afraid of fathers in China?
لا تخاف من الآباء في الصين؟
Sometimes when I think about it,
أحيانًا عندما أفكر في الأمر ،
I think your mother is right.
أعتقد أن والدتك على حق.
Why should I treat my son badly?
لماذا يجب أن أعامل ابني معاملة سيئة؟
You've grown up day by day,
لقد كبرت يومًا بعد يوم ،
and I'm getting old
وأنا أتقدم في السن
day by day.
يوما بعد يوم.
Time
زمن
flies
يطير
when we are
عندما نكون
still confronting each other day by day.
ما زلنا نواجه بعضنا البعض يوما بعد يوم.
But
ولكن
our stubbornness has its root.
عنادنا جذوره.
When your grandpa was alive,
عندما كان جدك على قيد الحياة ،
on one Mid-Autumn Festival,
في مهرجان منتصف الخريف ،
he told me to take you back for dinner.
قال لي أن آخذك لتناول العشاء.
As a result.
نتيجة ل.
I agreed.
قد وافقت.
But I forgot it because I was busy at school.
لكني نسيت ذلك لأنني كنت مشغولاً في المدرسة.
Your grandpa
جدك
scolded me for a whole month.
وبخني لمدة شهر كامل.
Do you remember?
هل تذكر؟
I...
أنا...
I remember it.
أتذكرها.
Actually, I haven't fully remembered
في الواقع ، لم أتذكر تمامًا
many things.
اشياء كثيرة.
Today
اليوم
is the happiest day for your mom
هو أسعد يوم لأمك
these days.
هذه الأيام.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
I
أنا
watched a TV series a while ago.
شاهدت المسلسل التلفزيوني منذ فترة.
There is a line
هناك خط
that is very good.
هذا جيد جدا.
The world
العالم
is an echo valley.
هو وادي صدى.
If you miss someone,
إذا كنت تفتقد شخص ما ،
just shout out loud.
فقط اصرخ بصوت عال.
Sooner or later,
عاجلا أم آجلا،
no matter how far he is from you,
لا يهم كم هو بعيد عنك
he can still hear you.
لا يزال بإمكانه سماعك.
You've grown to this big,
لقد نمت إلى هذا الحجم الكبير ،
and I've never talked so much to you.
ولم أتحدث معك كثيرًا أبدًا.
Why did I talk so much today?
لماذا تحدثت كثيرا اليوم؟
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
All right.
حسنا.
Let's stop here.
دعنا نتوقف هنا.
We're leaving.
كانوا يغادرون.
Honey,
عسل،
let's go back.
دعنا نعود.
It's still early.
لا يزال الوقت مبكرا.
Stay a bit longer.
ابق لفترة أطول قليلاً.
-Come on. Have a seat. -Are you leaving or not?
-هيا.  تفضل بالجلوس.  -هل سترحل أم لا؟
If you don't leave, I'll leave first.
إذا لم ترحل ، سأغادر أولاً.
Okay.
تمام.
Okay, wait.
حسنا انتظر.
Let's leave together.
دعنا نترك معا.
Jin,
جين ،
son,
ابن،
we are leaving.
نحن مغادرون.
Come home when you have time.
تعال إلى المنزل عندما يكون لديك وقت.
I'll cook something delicious for you.
سأطبخ شيئًا لذيذًا لك.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Bye.
وداعا.
Thank you. Please come again, Uncle.
شكرًا لك.  من فضلك تعال مرة أخرى يا عم.
Okay.
تمام.
-Jin. -See you.
-جن.  -أرك لاحقًا.
You should come to my house, too.
يجب أن تأتي إلى منزلي أيضًا.
Son, take Jin to our house.
بني ، خذ جين إلى منزلنا.
Well. Bye, Uncle and Auntie.
نحن سوف.  وداعا العم والعم.
Take care.
يعتني.
Bye.
وداعا.
Jin Ayin.
جين عين.
I...
أنا...
really envy Chi Yu.
حقا الحسد تشي يو.
Thank you, Mom.
شكرا لك أمي.
Don't move.
.لا تتحرك
Your hands are dirty.
يديك متسختين.
Don't break it.
لا تكسرها.
How is it?
كيف هذا؟
Look, your Uncle Qian gave it to me.
انظر ، أعطاها لي عمك تشيان.
Is it pretty?
هل هذا جميل؟
Mom.
أم.
Today
اليوم
is my birthday.
هو عيد ميلادي.
At that time, I thought
في ذلك الوقت ، فكرت
she finally remembered it once.
تذكرته أخيرًا مرة واحدة.
Even just once is good.
حتى مرة واحدة فقط جيد.
Did she come to you
هل هي اتت اليك
after you became famous?
بعد ان اشتهرت
Didn't the book say
ألم يقل الكتاب
she had no children in her life?
ليس لديها أطفال في حياتها؟
She never accepted me.
لم تقبلني قط.
Then, she's not as greedy
إذن ، فهي ليست جشعة
as you said.
كما قلت.
If she really loved vanity,
إذا كانت تحب الغرور حقًا ،
she would want the whole world to know
كانت تريد أن يعرف العالم كله
you are her son.
انت ابنها.
That way,
من ذلك الطريق،
she can make more money
يمكنها كسب المزيد من المال
and become more famous.
وتصبح أكثر شهرة.
In my opinion,
فى رايى،
she just
إنها فقط
wanted to make you think she's bad,
أردت أن تجعلك تعتقد أنها سيئة ،
so that you wouldn't
حتى لا تفعل
have anything to do with her.
لها أي علاقة بها.
Sometimes,
بعض الأحيان،
we can't just listen to what others say,
لا يمكننا الاستماع فقط إلى ما يقوله الآخرون ،
but watch what they do.
لكن شاهد ما يفعلونه.
Maybe
يمكن
I'm the unqualified son.
أنا الابن غير المؤهل.
Jin Ayin.
جين عين.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
[The world is an echo valley.]
[العالم وادي صدى.]
[The thunder in the valley travels thousands of miles.]
[يقطع الرعد في الوادي آلاف الأميال].
[Waves after waves.]
[موجات بعد موجات.]